A world of wonders in one great picture!
Alice in Wonderland is a animation, family, fantasy
film directed by Clyde Geronimi.
On a golden afternoon, wildly curious young Alice tumbles into the burrow and enters
the merry, madcap world of Wonderland full of whimsical escapades.
Alice (voice), played by Kathryn Beaumont.
Mad Hatter (voice), played by Ed Wynn.
Caterpillar (voice), played by Richard Haydn.
Cheshire Cat (voice), played by Sterling Holloway.
March Hare (voice), played by Jerry Colonna.
Queen of Hearts (voice), played by Verna Felton.
Alice in Wonderland is a 1951 American animated musical fantasy comedy film
produced by Walt Disney Productions and released by RKO Radio Pictures.
It is based on Lewis Carroll's 1865 novel Alice's Adventures in
Wonderland and its 1871 sequel Through the Looking-Glass.
The production was supervised by Ben Sharpsteen, and was directed by
Clyde Geronimi, Wilfred Jackson, and Hamilton Luske.
With the voices of Ed Wynn, Richard Haydn, Sterling Holloway, Jerry Colonna and Kathryn Beaumont in her film debut, the film follows a young girl, Alice, who falls down a rabbit hole
and enters a nonsensical world, Wonderland, which is ruled by the Queen of Hearts, while encountering strange creatures, including the Mad Hatter and the Cheshire Cat.
Walt Disney was supposed to make his first film Alice which was supposed to star Mary Pickford as Alice,
but he chose not to do the film  and instead did Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937).
However, the idea was eventually revived in the 1940s,
following the success of Snow White.
The film was originally intended to be a live-action/animated film, but
Disney decided it would be a fully animated feature film.
During its production, many sequences adapted from Carroll's books were later omitted, such
as Jabberwocky, the White Knight, the Duchess, Mock Turtle and the Gryphon.
Alice in Wonderland premiered at the Leicester Square Theatre in London on
July 26, 1951, and was released in New York City on July 28.
The film was also shown on television as one of
the first episodes of Disneyland.
It was initially considered a box-office failure, grossing $2.4 million
domestically, and received negative reviews from critics.
However, its 1974 theatrical re-release achieved greater success, leading to additional reissues,
merchandising, and home video releases as critical reception improved over time.
The film explores themes of dreams, based on novel
or book, heart, queen, villain.
The tone is lighthearted.